<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Shikshya Dahal</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Shikshya Dahal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Customer segmentation of retail dataset using kmeans clustering algorithm</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/projects/customer_segmentation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/projects/customer_segmentation/</guid><description>Customer Segmentation
customer segmentation is a process of dividing customers into different groups based on their characteristics. This can be useful for mall management in order to better understand their customers and tailor marketing strategies to different groups. One popular method for customer segmentation is k-means clustering, which is a machine learning technique that groups similar data points together. In this article, we will be discussing how to use the k-means algorithm in Python to perform customer segmentation for a mall.</description></item><item><title>Extracting entities mentioned in the tweets posted by Former U.S president Trump, analyze the sentiment associated with it and visualize the data using Tableau</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/projects/trump_tweet_analysis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/projects/trump_tweet_analysis/</guid><description>Millions of individuals, including politicians, use the well-liked social networking site Twitter to tweet about their ideas and experiences. Because of this, there is a substantial amount of text data available in the form of tweets that may be examined and used to learn important lessons. Extracting entities from the tweets, such as names of people, organizations, locations, and more, is one method of analyzing this text data. An additional method is to conduct sentiment analysis, which is the process of figuring out the sentiment or emotion communicated in a text.</description></item><item><title>Topic modeling of Depression posts scraped from reddit</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/projects/topic_modeling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/projects/topic_modeling/</guid><description>Topic modeling is a statistical modeling that can be used to discover hidden (latent) themes from the collection of documents. Having information about the problems and opinions about a certain product or services can be very important for businesses. But discovering themes in a large mine of online reviews or comments in the internet can be a expensive process. Thus, several algorithms like NMF, LDA, BERT can be employed for this purpose.</description></item></channel></rss>