<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NER on Shikshya Dahal</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/tags/ner/</link><description>Recent content in NER on Shikshya Dahal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/tags/ner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Extracting entities mentioned in the tweets posted by Former U.S president Trump, analyze the sentiment associated with it and visualize the data using Tableau</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/projects/trump_tweet_analysis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/projects/trump_tweet_analysis/</guid><description>Millions of individuals, including politicians, use the well-liked social networking site Twitter to tweet about their ideas and experiences. Because of this, there is a substantial amount of text data available in the form of tweets that may be examined and used to learn important lessons. Extracting entities from the tweets, such as names of people, organizations, locations, and more, is one method of analyzing this text data. An additional method is to conduct sentiment analysis, which is the process of figuring out the sentiment or emotion communicated in a text.</description></item><item><title>NER</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/nlp/project-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/nlp/project-4/</guid><description>NER refers to the IE task of identifying the entities in a document. Entities are typically names of persons, locations, and organizations, and other specialized strings, such as money expressions, dates, products, names/numbers of laws or articles, and so on. NER is an important step in the pipeline of several NLP applications involving information extraction.
A simple approach to building an NER system is to maintain a large collection of person/organization/location names that are the most relevant to our company (e.</description></item></channel></rss>