<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hello 🌼 on Shikshya Dahal</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/</link><description>Recent content in Hello 🌼 on Shikshya Dahal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Day 1- Feature Scaling</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/30-days-of-ml/project-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/30-days-of-ml/project-1/</guid><description>Feature Scaling Feature scaling is one of the most important transformation in most of the ML projects. When one feature is on small range; say 0 to 10 while the other one is on a large range (suppose 0 to 10000); ML algorithms donot perform well. We have to scale the features so that both of them takes a comparable ranges of values to each other. In simpler terms, it means transforming data into a common range of values.</description></item><item><title>NLP 1: NLP pipelines</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/nlp/project-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/nlp/project-1/</guid><description>NLP :
&amp;ldquo;As we all know, dealing with natural language is hard. It is hard from the standpoint of the child, who must spend many years acquiring a language (compare this time span to that required for the acquisition of motor skills such as eating solids, walking, or swimming), it is hard for the adult language learner, it is hard for the scientist who attempts to model the relevant phenomena, and it is hard for the engineer who attempts to build systems that deal with natural language input or output.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/about/</guid><description>About: Hi. My Name is Shikshya Dahal. I am an Information Management Graduate with specialization in Data Science and AI. Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m working as a Machine Learning Developer and most of my works are in NLP and Conversational AI. Data science has always been my passion. I am good at handling data and I have a solid foundation and experience in building ML and statistical models. I find exploring and visualizing insights hidden in data to develop data driven solutions that aids in decision making more than admirable.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/contact/</guid><description>Reach out to me on these platforms:
platform URL Github: https://github.com/shikshya1 Gmail: shikshyadahal@gmail.com Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/shikshya-dahal/</description></item></channel></rss>