<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Serverless on Shikshya Dahal</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/tags/serverless/</link><description>Recent content in Serverless on Shikshya Dahal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/tags/serverless/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create a trigger to upload data in csv files to DynamoDB when csv is inserted on S3 via Lambda function using Serverless Framework</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/aws/project-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/aws/project-2/</guid><description>This project demonstrates how to process a csv file when inserted on s3 bucket and use the data to populate DynamoDB table. DynamoDB is a fully managed, serverless, key-value NoSQL database designed to run high-performance applications at any scale.I am only using DynamoDB in this project for test purpose as it is a bad choice when we are dealing with small size of data.
Steps Initialize a aws-python template from serverless framework We then need to import boto3 (Python SDK that allows us to interact with DynamoDB and S3), pandas and s3fs (to read the csv file) library.</description></item><item><title>Deploy lambda function with external python packages using serverless framework.</title><link>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/aws/project-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://shikshya1.github.io/portfolio/aws/project-1/</guid><description>Lambda Function &amp;amp; Layers: AWS Lambda is a computing service that allows us to run our code without the overhead of configuring and managing a server. It can be scaled automatically based on the request and the charge is calculated only for the compute time. Lambda function can be deployed using .zip file archive that contains function and the dependency or using container image. Lambda layers can be used to package external dependencies that is required to run lambda function.</description></item></channel></rss>